HAYDEN ROSS

Computer Scientist

@ haydenross00@gmail.com

1 +1 (514) 926-4722

Montreal, Canada

in hayden-ross21

HayRossSibz22

ABOUT ME

As a computer science graduate, I'm dedicated to excelling in a meaningful professional environment. With industry experience in quality assurance, as well as in depth knowledge of C++, C, and Java, I am a versatile hire ready to learn even more. I'm enthusiastic about contributing to a community that values innovation, building strong bonds, and creating exceptional user experiences.

TECH STACK

LANGUAGES

Java C C++ C# Python .NET Core JavaScript	English: Native
TypeScript MySQL HTML CSS React	French: Professional
Linux iOS Multiple Processor Coding GitHub	
VSCode Eclipse JIRA Microsoft Office	

WORK EXPERIENCE

Quality Assurance Specialist @ Matrox

i 08/2020-05/2021

Dorval, QC, Canada

- Demonstrated expertise in conducting rigorous tests on multiple builds, ensuring the delivery of fully functional products to customers. Effectively managed tests varying in complexity from sourcing from various operating systems to streaming over diverse web protocols.
- Conducted root cause analysis and troubleshooting to identify and communicate bugs promptly to relevant engineering teams via JIRA, resulting in swift resolutions and improved product quality.
- Conducted comparative analysis of competing streaming devices, designing and executing comprehensive tests to benchmark our services and devices against competitors. Communicated formalized results to cross-functional stakeholders, aiding in strategic decision-making.
- Contributed to knowledge sharing and process improvement by creating and documenting testing methods, tools, and technical specifications, including streaming protocols and batch files for automated testing. This documentation, as well as teaching essential skills and knowledge to new team members, facilitated onboarding and enhanced team efficiency.

Lead Marketer @ Student Works

12/2017-08/2018

Montreal, QC, Canada

- Efficiently managed job coordination, ensuring the smooth transition of equipment between sites and facilitating the introduction of employees to new customers.
- Proven track record of acquiring over 100 new customers through successful cold calling and door-to-door marketing efforts, significantly expanding the customer base and revenue.
- Provided comprehensive training and supervision to new employees, equipping them with essential sales skills
 necessary to excel in their roles and contribute to the company's growth.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science @ Conco	ordia University
2 019–2023	Montreal, Canada
Diploma of College Studies in Pure and A	applied Science @ Dawson College
2017–2019	■ Montreal, Canada
PROJECTS	
Digitized Risk Board Game in In C++ •	
📋 January 2022–April 2022	
 Collaborated with a team of 4 other Concor C++. 	rdia University students to recreate the classic Risk board game using
 Developed complex features, including dyn non-playable characters (NPCs). 	namic map integration from the internet and the inclusion of unique
 Employed formal methods to manage cross tion. 	s-functional complexity effectively, ensuring successful project execu-
Parallel Quicksort on Hypercube Using M	Iulti-Threading 🕠
September 2022–October 2022	
• Implemented a parallelized Quicksort algo	rithm in C++.
 Utilized multi-threading techniques to distribute leveraging modern multicore processors. 	ribute sorting tasks across multiple threads, enhancing performance by
 Designed and optimized the algorithm to repower of interconnected nodes. 	un on a hypercube topology, effectively utilizing the parallel processing
Machine Learning Models Determining W	/ater Potability 🕠
September 2022–December 2022	
 Led a collaborative effort with 3 other stude water safety for drinking purposes. 	ents to develop machine learning models in Python aimed at evaluating
 Leveraged data analytics and advanced pre- mize 9 generated models and identify the n 	eprocessing techniques, including recursive feature elimination, to opti- nost efficient one.
 Presented results to a Concordia University mization. Achieved a minimum accuracy of 	Professor, demonstrating strong skills in model comparison and opti- 80% for the generated models.
Utilized GitHub for seamless collaboration	and version control throughout the project.

INTERESTS

- Painting: digital and traditional @WhatsHaydenCreatin
- Sketch Comedy
- Traveling
- Rock Climbing: bouldering and deep soloing
- Weight Training